

# Barbara Gigerl

- barbara.gigerl@gmail.com
- ★ Katzianergasse 4, 8010 Graz
- barbaragigerl

#### **About Me**

I am currently a PhD Student at Graz University of Technology, Austria. I am part of the Secure Systems group at the Institute of Applied Information Processing and Communications. My research interests include side-channel analysis on secure systems, especially power-analysis attacks and countermeasures.

#### Personal Data

Dipl-Ing. Dipl-Ing. Barbara Gigerl, BSc BSc

Born December 21st, 1994 in Deutschlandsberg

tion Windows in Spectre Attacks

Citizenship Austria

Languages German (mother tongue), English (C1-B2), Spanish (A2), Mandarin (A1)

Interests and Hobbies Creative writing and poetry slams, Volleyball, participating in CTF

competitions with LosFuzzys (the university's CTF team)

#### Education

since 2019	<b>Graz University of Technology</b> , PhD studies, advisor: Stefan Mangard Research area: security of embedded systems, side-channel attacks, power analysis, implementation and development of countermeasures
2017- 2019	Graz University of Technology, Master degrees with distinction  Computer Science, thesis: Utility of Transfer Entropy for the Extraction of Influence Networks  Software Engineering and Management, thesis: Automated Analysis of Specula-

2014- 2017	Graz University of Technology, Bachelor degrees with distinction  Computer Science Software Development and Business Management Thesis: A Generic Side-Channel Protected AES Implementation for 32-bit RISC-V Processors
2009- 2014	HTBLA Kaindorf, Matura with distinction Focus: Electronic Data Processing and Management
2001- 2009	Primary and secondary school in Eibiswald

## Work and Teaching Experience

since 2019	Graz University of Technology University Assistant
2018	Information Management Systems Institute, Athena RC Summer Internship in Athens, research about fake news detection in social media
2017	<b>Graz University of Technology</b> Summer Internship at the Institute of Applied Information Processing and Communications, research about the application of formal methods in machine learning environments
2016- 2019	Graz University of Technology Study Assistant at the Institute of Applied Information Processing and Communications Courses: Operating Systems, Systems Programming, Logic and Computability
2016	LOGICDATA Electronic & Software Entwicklungs GmbH Summer Internship, IT system administraion and network maintenance
2015- 2016	Snowreporter Telekommunikationssystemme GmbH Part-time, web development
2015	evolaris next level GmbH Summer Internship, web development
2012- 2015	Jungheinrich Systemlösungen GmbH Summer Internship, software development and warehouse optimization

## Talks and Presentations

May 2019 Transient Execution Attacks: Still hARMful?.

Barbara Gigerl, Claudio Canella

Qualcomm Product Security Summit, San Diego, California, USA

### **Awards**

December Würdigungspreis des BMWFW 2019

2019 State Prize of the Republic of Austria (Staatspreis) of the Federal Ministry for Educa-

tion, Science and Research for the best master and diploma degree students

Juni 2014 Hofrat-Trummer Medaille 2014

Award as best student of the final year 2014 at HTBLA Kaindorf